A Guide to the Papers of John Preston Moore ca. 1822-1925
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of John Preston Moore ca. 1822-1925
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11378
ca. 600 items (1.5 Hollinger boxes)
The papers of John Preston Moore (1841-1911) of Kerr's Creek, Rockbridge County, Virginia, ca. 1822-1925, ca. 600 items (1.5 Hollinger boxes), chiefly consists of legal and financial papers, including accounts, tax receipts, canceled checks, and receipts of John Preston Moore, and financial papers of Moore & Laird and Laird & Dunlap. Also present is Moore's correspondence, bound volumes, specifications for a house belonging to Frank Moore, and some printed materials, which were transferred to the Rare Books Division.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The collection is without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the University of Virginia Library from the History Broker, Roanoke, Virginia, on January 23, 1998.
Biographical/Historical Information
John Preston Moore served with the Kerr's Creek Confederates, the 58th Virginia Infantry, in the Civil War, as a captain in Company G, where he was wounded in 1862 at Port Republic. He commanded the post in Lexington from August 1864 until April 1865, and an order book from this period is in this collection (Box 2). Following his military service, Moore became a deputy sheriff in Rockbridge County, 1865-1870, the clerk of court in Lexington, 1870-1893, and a lawyer in Lexington from 1893 until his death in 1911, when he was buried in the Stonewall Jackson Cemetery.
Scope and Content Information
The papers of John Preston Moore (1841-1911) of Kerr's Creek, Rockbridge County, Virginia, ca. 1822-1925, ca. 600 items (1.5 Hollinger boxes), chiefly consists of legal and financial papers, including accounts, tax receipts, canceled checks, and receipts of John Preston Moore, and financial papers of Moore & Laird and Laird & Dunlap. Also present is Moore's correspondence, bound volumes, specifications for a house belonging to Frank Moore, and some printed materials, which were transferred to the Rare Books Division.
The correspondence is chiefly concerned with business matters and correspondents include: John T. Armstrong, J.C. Ballard (briefly concerning Buena Vista and mining speculation, 1889 Dec 14), James H. Bell, James Bumgardner, Jr., F.D. Coe, William M. Dunlap (briefly concerning Buena Vista, 1889 Dec 31), James Goodbar, James Housten, Charles H. Kitchel, T.C. Leake, Jr. (briefly concerning Buena Vista, 1889 Dec 31), James McDonald (concerning the effort of the state of Virginia in collecting the names of all who served in the Confederate forces, 1884 May 2), Morton Marye, E.B. Moon, O. Howard Royer, John C. Shields, Miss M.L. Starke, and Thomas H. Tutwiler.
Contents List
- Accounts of John Preston Moore 1866-1890 (Box 1)
- Canceled Checks of John Preston Moore 1868-1881 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, chiefly of John Preston Moore 1869-1890, 1924-1925 (Box 1)
- Financial Papers 1859-1884, n.d. (Box 1)
- Financial Papers of Laird & Moore and Laird & Dunlap 1822-1865, n.d., 2 folders (Box 1)
- Legal & Miscellaneous Papers 1861-1889 (Box 1)
- Receipts of John Preston Moore 1868-1889 (Box 1)
- "Specifications for a House for Frank Moore, of Lexington," and an unidentified residence n.d. (Box 1)
- Account Book, with index, of [John Preston Moore ?] 1865-1874, Bound volume (Box 2)
- Bank of Lexington Check Register of John Preston Moore (1870-1871); Record of the collection of claims (ca. 1839-1867); and Record of License Sales (1866-1869) ca.1839-1871, 3 bound volumes (Box 2)
- Memoranda Books of [John Preston Moore ?] ca. 1868-1888, 6 bound volumes (Box 2)
- Order Book of Captain John Preston Moore while Commanding Post, Lexington, Virginia 1865 Mar 27-Apr 10, Bound volume (Box 2)